Inventory of the Jiri Setina Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Agendas of meetings of the Presidium of the Department of National Security and the Political Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to church affairs and the liquidation of kulaks; proposals on Soviet consultants; statistics about Czechoslovak refugees; reports on the transfer of 800 families in Brno, and trials and imprisonment for political offenses (Box-folder 13: 1)
- Final report of the Commission of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on political trials in 1949-1953, parts I and II (Folder 13: 2)
- Report on the creation of a single Defense, Security, and Justice Department; personnel files of the Department of Interior; final report of the Commission of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on political trials in 1949–1954; report on employees of the Department of National Security relating to the use of violence during interrogations of prisoners (Folder 13: 3)
- Lawsuit of the police of the Czech Republic, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, against Karel Rusov (Russwurm), parts I and II (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
- Reports on the situation of the former Uniate (Greek-Catholic) Church in East Slovakia, activities of the Seventh-Day Adventists, the prisoner cleric Felix Davídek, and security during celebrations in the church sv. Víta in Prague in 1988, report for the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on the situation in Iraq, and on Ladislav Technik (Svobodné Slova), the Corps of National Security, activities of church representatives and the Mormons, the interrogation of Vojtěch Křížek, trials and imprisonment for political offenses, and the situation of national security; election of Jan Kotouč as head of the Evangelic Methodist Church; letters from bishop Ján Vojtaššák to Dean Eduard Bugár and vicar Scheffer; newspaper clipping about trials of agents Lorenc, Kincl, Vykypěl (Folder 14: 3)
- Reports on the situation of national security in 1969 and 1982, activities of the Corps of National Security, the border guards, and the troops under the Department of Interior, and trials and imprisonment for political offenses; proposal for a lawsuit against the group Russicum and for the reorganization of convents (Folder 14: 4)
- Reports on the situation of the former Uniate (Greek-Catholic) Church in East Slovakia, activities of the Seventh-Day Adventists, activities of the Christian-Democratic Party deputy František Kaďůrek, trials of church members, burials of bishops Robert Pobožný and Josef Hlouch, the religious ceremonies of Virgin Marie Svatohorská, the burial of bishop Karel Skoupý, and the surveillance of church services in Prague in 1949; report on the confiscated religious American movie Youth in Trouble; minutes of meetings of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to church affairs (Folder 14: 5)
- Personnel files of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to Pavel Minařík and Stanislav Staněk; private documents of Jiří Setina relating to his publication about communist crimes against the Czech population and civil society in 1945–1989. (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
  Includes the speech of Jiří Setina in Zurich entitled "What Does the Czech Republic Look Like in 1996?", correspondence with the Czech Catholic church, letters of congratulations on the nomination of Jiří Setina as attorney general of the Czech Republic, and newspaper clippings; reports on trials and imprisonment for political offenses and the Czech agent Stefan Kolman, shot to death by Oldřich Kvapil; application of Ivan Kočárník for membership in the Czechoslovak Communist Party
- Report on the trial of Ladislav Mácha relating to the death of priest Jan Toufar (Folder 15: 3-5)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to church affairs; evaluation of public opinion; plan of surveillance of churches (K operation) (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau and the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to church affairs (Folder 16: 2)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to trials of clerics and the amnesty for prisoners (Folder 16: 3)
- Lawsuit of the Police of the Czech Republic, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, against Karel Rusov (Russwurm), parts III and IV (Folder 16: 4-5)
- Documents on church archives, including minutes of meetings of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party, minutes of the meetings of the minister of national security, and minutes of meetings of the Office for Church Affairs (Box 17)
  - 1947-1950 (Folder 17: 1)
  - 1951-1954 (Folder 17: 2)
  - 1955-1970 (Folder 17: 3)
  - 1971-1991 (Folder 17: 4)
- Reports on national safety and security (Box 18)
  - 1969–1973 (Folder 18: 1)
  - 1977 (Folder 18: 2)
  - 1978-1980 (Folder 18: 3)
  - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - 1980-1981 (Folder 19: 2)
  - 1982-1986 (Folder 19: 3)
  - 1987-1989 (Folder 19: 4)
- Reports on the confiscation of Gestapo documents from Bohumil Siebert, and on Josef Vondráček; report of Minister of the Interior Václav Nosek on the Security Committee and activities of the Secret Service; minutes of meetings of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; personnel files of employees of section Z of the Department of Interior and of Marie Vosková (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Reports on activities of members of the Corps of National Security, trials and imprisonment of Stěpán Gavenda, Miloš Zemánek, and Juraj Dlouhý; personnel files of the Department of Interior; list of escaped deputies (Folder 20: 2)
- List of prisoners tortured during interrogations; working plan (October-December 1949) for the Security Section of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; proposal of Alexej Cepička to fill positions on the regional and provincial security commission; reports on Dr. Hromádka, Václav Tippl, trials for political offenses, and activities of Karel Sváb; minutes of meetings of the management of the State Security (Folder 20: 3)
- Interview of deputy Kudrny with Jindřich Veselý, Václav Aleš, Heda Synková, and Ladislav Kopřiva; statement of Jaroslav Procházka; final report on the case Cihošťský Zázrak; reports on criminal methods of the 2nd sector of the Department of Interior in 1949–1954, the removal of Bohumil Doubek from the Department of Interior, the removal of the statue of T. G. Masaryk in Prostějově, and activities of the administration of the Department of Interior; minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to the trial of Stěpán Plaček (Folder 20: 4)
- Report on trials for political offenses in 1953–1954 (Folder 20: 5)
- Report on interrogation methods of the 2nd sector of the Department of Interior in 1949–1954 (Folder 20: 6)
- Report on interrogation methods of the 1st sector of the Department of Interior in 1949–1954 (Folder 20: 7-8)
- Statements of employees of the Security Commission Ladislav Niewald and František Novák; minutes of meetings of the Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; two letters from Heda Synková; record of accused functionaries of Czech and Slovak parties; list of old prisoners (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Report on the development of the State Security in 1945-1967 (Folder 21: 2)
- Reports on death penalties, 1948–1950, the trial of Rudolf Barák, and final inquiries on political trials in 1949–1954 (Folder 21: 3)
- Reports of the Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on the Trotskyite group Neuman and on trials and death penalties for political offenses (Folder 21: 4)
- Reports on trials and death penalties for political offenses, interrogations of Jan Curák and Josef Trojan, and the investigation of illegal departures of trains going abroad; statement of Ladislav Zelenka relating to his work; personnel files of the Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; letter of Jiří Cermák relating to the complaint against Ladislav Kopřiva; minutes of meetings of the Political Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party (Folder 21: 5)
- Reports on trials and death penalties for political offenses; proposal on the dissolution and prohibition of Zionistic organizations, the nomination of a head prosecutor in the Slanský trial, and the use of prisoners in factory production; order of the minister of national security on burials of agents and terrorists; letter from Karel Sváb to Klement Gottwald (Folder 21: 6)
- Register of the State Regional Archives, Town Archives, State District Archives, and archives of special significance; private archive of Karel Klos, minister of justice (Box-folder 22: 1)
- Proposal on the reorganization of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; minutes of meetings of the board of the National Security Department and the Political Secretariat of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party; report on trials and imprisonment for political offenses; statistical survey of detainees of State Security (Folder 22: 2)
- Reports on dispatching of employees of the Department of Interior to capitalist countries, trials and imprisonment for political offenses, the custody of railroad borders, and activities of the 2nd Special Division of the Department of Interior; statistical survey of Czech refugees in foreign countries; statute of the administration of the Department of Interior (Folder 22: 3)
- Report on the Karel and Farský operations (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Report on the internment of officers in forced labor camps (Folder 23: 2-3)
- Report on the surveillance of citizens (Folder 23: 4)
- Reports on the surveillance and interrogation of
  - Michal Cernega (Charta 77) (Folder 23: 5)
  - Svatopluk Karásek (Folder 23: 6)
  - Vlastimil Třešňák (Charta 77) (Folder 23: 7)
- Personnel files of Jan Piller, Zdeněk Mlynář, Vasil Bilak, Joseph Lenárt, Zbyněk Soják, Drahomír Kolder, Alois Indra, and Emil Rigo; list of interned Hungarians (Folder 23: 8)
- Personnel file of Pavel Landovský (Folder 23: 9)
- Personnel file of Ivan Fiala (pseudonym Albatros) relating to the Prolog and Akropulos operations (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Reports on the Věra operation relating to the surveillance of Klement Lukeš, Robert Horák, and Miloš Vavruška, parts I, II and III (Folder 24: 2-4)
- Survey on the structure of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party, 1945–1989, and the functionaries of Central Organs of the Czechoslovak Communist Party, 1945–1989; reports on the staff of the Corps of National Security (VKR) in August 1968 (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Proposal on the observation of illegal group activities; minutes of meetings of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to criminal laws and cooperation between organs of the Department of Interior; order of the leader of the administration of the Corps of National Security on the establishment of a counter-intelligence main management; personnel files of the Department of Interior; report on safety and security in Czechoslovakia and results of negotiations between Czechoslovak and Soviet ministers of interior in August 1989 (Folder 25: 2)
- Reports on the political trial of Gustav Husák and activities of Gustav Husák and Novomeský in 1939-1941 (Folder 25: 3)
- Reports on the 9th congress of the Slovak Communist Party, the interrogation of Bedřich Reicin, and trials of Rudolf Barák and Osvald Závodský (Folder 25: 4)
- Dissertation of Zdeněk Boháč about the escape of Czechoslovak citizens into nonsocialist countries; working plan of the administration of the State Security in Hradec Králové for the years 1979-1982; surveillance reports of the military police on fortifications and obstacles on the Czechoslovak- German and Czechoslovak-Austrian borders and on the Carpatho-Ukraine border; minutes of meetings of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to the invasion of Prague by Warsaw Pact troops in 1968 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Report on the evaluation of annual work plans for 1978-1985 of the administration of the State Security in Ustí nad Labem and České Budějovice (Folder 26: 2)
- Report on the evaluation of annual work plans for 1980-1983 of the administration of the State Security in Ústí nad Labem; quarterly information report on problems of the administration of the Corps of National Security in Plzeň, 1984-1986 (Folder 26: 3)
- Personnel files of the Czech police, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, on Zdeněk Němec, Oldřich Mezl, and Bohumil Carda; personnel files of the Czech police in Hradec Králové, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, on Vladimír Krejčík, Antonín Valter, Josef Kroulík, et al. (Folder 26: 4)
- Personnel files of the Czech police in Ceské Budejovice and Ustí nad Labem, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism (Folder 26: 5)
- Reports of the Department of Interior on the Jarov 83, Klánovice, and Oliva 88 operations, including descriptions of microphone installation in the apartment of Karel Havlík in Prague (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Reports on trials of State Security employees and of Jan Hora on problems of State Security employees, (1948; 1964) (Folder 27: 2)
- Statements of Otmar Kašina, Antonín Kavan, Andrej Keppert, Antonín Prchal, and Karel Košťál relating to their activities in the party; list of employees of the 6th sector of the Department of Interior, (1951–1959) (Folder 27: 3)
- Personnel files of the Department of Interior; report on trials of State Security employees, (1956; 1964) (Folder 27: 4)
- Statements of employees of the 2nd sector of the Department of Interior, (1962–1963) (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Statements and interrogations of Corps of National Security employees, (1951–1964) (Folder 28: 2)
- Report on the examination of Corps of National Security employee Václav Líbal and testimonies (Folder 28: 3)
- Personnel files of the Department of Interior; reports on the situation of the State Security in Czechoslovakia, the analysis of criminal activities in the Military Court, and the reorganization of the regional administrations of the Department of Interior, (1954–1961; 1968, 1969) (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Reports on the situation of the Department of Interior, and the number of employees in regional administrations of the Department of Interior (Folder 29: 2)
- Proposal on the renewal of the proof of evidence for convicted individuals; activity report and work plan of the 4th Special Division of the Department of Interior (1953–1954); list of deceased prisoners between 1948 January 1 and 1968 June 30 (Folder 29: 3)
- Reports on activities of the guerilla brigade Mistr Jan Hus in 1964 (Folder 29: 4)
- Reports on interrogation methods referring to the political trials of 1949–1954, of the Commission of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on political prisoners in 1949–1954, and on activities of the Department of National Security (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Report on the development of the State Security in 1945-1967 (Folder 30: 2)
- Minutes of meetings of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to the amendment of §109, church affairs, and the emigration of Czech citizens; reports on the death of the prisoner Pavel Wonka, the political situation between August 15 and 22 1988, in regard to the 20th anniversary of August 1968, and the regional political situation between 1988 October 27 and 30; statement on the proposal of the minister of interior relating to the change in structure of the Department of Interior (Folder 30: 3)
- Minutes of meetings of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to activities during celebrations of the CSR, the political situation in 1988 December, and the aims and general tasks of the Corps of National Security, the Frontier Guard, and the troops under the Department of Interior for the year 1989; proposal on the change of the party structure of the Federal Department of Interior; order of the People's Militia commander; report on foreign broadcasting jamming (Folder 30: 4)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to an agreement between the Department of Interior and Hungarian armed forces minister Muennich, and trials of Jiří Kárný, Otto Eisler, Vilém Stanovský, Jaroslav Nebesář, Jan Bárta, et al.; letter from Stefan Rais to Rudolf Barák (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to verifications of employees of departments and central offices; government decision of 1958 March 14; reports on activities of the National Security Department in 1949–1954, and activities of justice organs during political trials; proposal on trials of collaborators of Rudolf Slanský (Folder 31: 2)
- Report of Karol Bacílek on his activity in the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party in 1963; personnel files of the Presidium and the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party and the Department of Interior; report of the Department of Justice on collaborators of Rudolf Slanský; letter of the attorney general about convicted social democrats (Folder 31: 3)
- Report of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on trials for political offenses; interview with Vladimír Kohoutek about activities of Soviet consultants in 1955 July (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Reports of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on trials for political offenses, and of the minister of interior, minister of justice, and the attorney general on the situation of Czech prisons in 1956 (Folder 32: 2)
- Reports of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on trials for political offenses, and of the minister of interior, minister of justice, and the attorney general on the situation of Czech prisons in 1956; working plan of the administration of the Department of Interior; minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to employees honored with medals (Folder 32: 3)
- Report of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to Czech citizens in foreign countries (after August 1968); dissertation of Zdeněk Boháč; report for the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on censoring letters and foreign broadcasting jamming; letter of Jindřich Veselý (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Reports of the Government Commission for Persecution of Nazi crimes on their activities, of the minister of interior on safety and security, of the Presidium of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party on trials for political offenses and on the 16th Czechoslovak Communist Party congress (Folder 33: 2)
- Reports on interrogation reforms, chief problems in the Department of Interior, and statistics about criminality in 1970; minutes of meetings of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to rehabilitations of prisoners (Folder 33: 3)
- Trials of Božena Vltavská, Karel Lébr, Josef Martínek, Josef Hůrka, Josef Měřička, Jiří Buřil, Karel Janouch, Rudolf Kolena, and Vladimír Cerný (Box 34)
  - Part I (Folder 34: 1)
  - Part II (Folder 34: 2)
  - Appendix (Folder 34: 3-4)
- Reports on activities of justice organs during the period of political trials and of the Commission of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to the period of political processes in 1949–1953 (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Trials of Jaroslav Zajíc, Otakar Beck, Karla Hlubocká, Josef Hlubocký, Josef Holeček, Miroslav Livora, Božena Livorová, Josef Martínek, Jan Síma, Bohumil Vejdělek, and Salamoun Welkes
  - Documentation (Folder 35: 2)
  - Appendix (Folder 35: 3)
- Statements of employees of the Department of Interior relating to their activities (Folder 35: 4)
  - 1955-1957
    A - K
  - 1955-1957 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    L – R
  - 1955–1957 (Folder 36: 2)
    R - Z
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to trials of commanders Bohumil Doubek and Vladimír Kohoutek; report on activities of the Commission for Inquiries of Political Trials, 1949–1954 (Box-folder 37: 1)
- Minutes of meetings of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party relating to trials of individuals with major political functions (Folder 37: 2)
- Report on individuals with major political functions (Folder 37: 3)
- Proposal on working plans of the Corps of National Security in Ostrava; orders of the minister of interior (Box-folder 38: 1)
- Lawsuits of the police of the Czech Republic, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, against Bohumil Paukert, Josef Sobáň, and Josef Gába; proposal on work plans of the Corps of National Security in Ostrava (Folder 38: 2)
- Proposal on work plans of the Corps of National Security in Plzeň, Brno, Hradec Králové, Brno, and Ceské Budějovice; lawsuit of the police of the Czech Republic, Department of Documentation and Examination of Crimes of Communism, against Jan Puklický (Folder 38: 3)
- Memorabilia--Medals
  - Za službu vlasti (Folder 38: 4)
    (shift for the fatherland)
  - Stráž Národní Bezpečnosti, SNB (Folder 38: 5)
    (Guard of the National Security)
  - Za vynikající práci (Folder 38: 6)
    (excellent work)
- Closed (Box 39)